i mean who can eat millions of cookies
in one night and not get fat right well
i can
can you go ho ho
i don't go ho ho ho that's a myth
fake news what's not fake news is we are
making eggnog ice cream this week
so if you want to know how we make ours
stick around and we'll show you
[Music]
eggnog ice cream is everywhere on the
internet it's probably just come out of
the woodwork because of christmas
chronicles
but this is our version it's quite
similar to the other ones but i mean how
many different ways can you make eggnog
i guess
but here just add your cream your brown
sugar white sugar skimmed milk powder
and the egg yolks into your pan
whisk them up well and bring them all up
to 82 degrees c that's the easiest way
to make a custard base no faffing around
but the old school methods here
once that's ready take it off the heat
and add it into a container
at that point add in your double cream
or heavy cream and then finally add
your drink of choice i'm using old j
spiced rum here
and finally a nice good
splash of nutmeg
once it's ready put it in the fridge
until it's completely chilled
now for this ice cream make sure that
your machine is pre-chilled well there's
loads of booze in here
once it's ready and the machine is nice
and cold
get it in and get it churning
this took 13 minutes in my 50 30.
when it's ready take it out and load up
your tub i mean look at this tub it's
beautiful
[Music]
it's not even sunday morning it's all
gone a bit weird this week it's
wednesday
midweek ice cream anyone anyway let's
get this ice cream out the freezer and
see what it looks like there we go i
mean the loads of booze in here 70 70
odd mil of
very strong alcohol has gone in here now
obviously with the ice cream
alcohol depresses the freezing point so
you had too much it won't freeze so i've
dropped the sugar just a little bit to
compensate some of that
the egg yolks are really orange
it's not a bad thing
texture looks amazing let's see what it
tastes like
[Music]
there's a chubby chase quote i'm going
to put right here
let's go let's go
this is really nice really nice
obviously
the alcohol i've put in here i like to
drink
you're free to use whatever you like
whiskey rum whatever you fancy putting
in there make it nice and strong that's
half the point of eggnog apparently in
the uk we don't really do eggnog it's
coming in
slowly but surely
many years ago i had some from a carton
and it was shocking
the bad stuff and i said i would never
have it again but
we're gonna try and make some actual
real eggnog this weekend
i'm not gonna put booze in it because my
wife doesn't really drink so i'll just
have to add some in after just you know
because i can
anyway i hope you enjoy this video and i
hope you try this one it's really strong
really nice
don't forget to like and subscribe
and this may be the last video of the
year so if we don't see you until 2022
merry christmas
[Music]